It takes a moment to change history. It takes love to change lives.
Pearl Harbor is a war, romance, history film directed by Michael Bay.
The lifelong friendship between Rafe McCawley and Danny Walker is put to the ultimate test when the two ace
fighter pilots become entangled in a love triangle with beautiful Naval nurse Evelyn Johnson.
But the rivalry between the friends-turned-foes is immediately put on hold when they find
themselves at the center of Japan's devastating attack on Pearl Harbor on Dec.
Rafe McCawley, played by Ben Affleck.
Evelyn Johnson, played by Kate Beckinsale.
Danny Walker, played by Josh Hartnett.
Doris Miller, played by Cuba Gooding Jr..
Franklin D. Roosevelt, played by Jon Voight.
Earl Sistern, played by Tom Sizemore.
Pearl Harbor is a 2001 American romantic war drama film directed by Michael Bay,
produced by Bay and Jerry Bruckheimer and written by Randall Wallace.
Starring Ben Affleck, Josh Hartnett, Kate Beckinsale, Cuba Gooding Jr., Tom Sizemore, Jon Voight, Colm Feore, and Alec Baldwin, the film features a heavily
fictionalized version of the attack on Pearl Harbor, focusing on a love triangle set amidst the lead up to the attack, its aftermath, and the Doolittle Raid.
The film was produced by Touchstone Pictures and Jerry Bruckheimer Films and released by Buena Vista Pictures Distribution on May 25, 2001, and was a box office success, grossing $59 million in its opening weekend and $449.2 million worldwide, becoming the sixth highest-grossing film
of 2001, but received mixed-to-negative reviews from critics, who panned the performances (as well as the chemistry between the lead actors), its three-hour runtime and historical inaccuracies, but was praised for the visual effects, action sequences and music score.
It was nominated for four Academy Awards, winning in the category of Best Sound Editing, but
was also nominated for six Golden Raspberry Awards, including Worst Picture.
The film explores themes of army, airplane, nurse, patriotism, hawaii.
The tone is emotional.